Long Island Railroad Strike Newspaper Clippings 5963m
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Long Island Railroad Strike Newspaper Clippings
1994
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Belzer, Mike
5963m
1 folders
1 file folder.
Records (documents).
Newspaper clippings documenting the Long Island Railroad strike in 1994.
5743725
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
E. Parker, December 23, 2016
EAD encoding:
E. Parker, March 09, 2017
Biographical / Historical
On June 17, 1994, the conductors and maintenance workers of the Long Island Railroad (LIRR) went on strike, after two and a half years without a contract. The strike was led by the United Transportation Union (UTU) after negotiations concerning pay rates and work rules between the UTU and the Metropolitan Tranportation Authority (MTA), the LIRR's parent company, broke down. The strike lasted for two days until New York Governor Mario M. Cuomo and his aides stepped in to impose a contract settlement on the LIRR management, ending the contract dispute.
Scope and Contents
Inclusive date range: 1994
Bulk date: 1994
This collection consists of newspaper clippings from various New York City newspapers documenting the Long Island Railroad strike in 1994.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: /3052: John W. McConnell Papers /4164: Harrison M. Trice Additional Papers /4284: Robert B. McKersie Additional Papers 5012: Saul Wallen Papers 5034: Switchmen's Union of North America Records 5052: U.S. Emergency Board No. 129 Records 5102: Emergency Board No. 129, Long Island Railroad and the Brotherhood of Railroad Trainmen, Locals 517 and 1090, Records 5129: Maxwell Copelof Arbitration Briefs, Exhibits, Transcripts and Decisions 5141: Brotherhood of Locomotive Firemen and Enginemen Records 5149: Brotherhood of Railroad Trainmen Records 5217: Jacob Seidenberg Additional Arbitration Case Files 5229: Jacob Seidenberg Additional records 5348: W.P. Kennedy as President of the Brotherhood of Railroad Trainmen against the Long Island Railroad Company Court Documents 5478: AFL-CIO Railway Employees' Department Records 5478 mf: AFL-CIO Railway Employees' Department Records on Microfilm 5484: Railway Labor Executives' Association Records 5488 B: BRAC Records 5512: Arnold Zack Arbitration Files 5538: James C. Hill Arbitration Files 5539: Benjamin H. Wolf Additional Arbitration Files 5551: Arnold M. Zack Additional Arbitration Files 5552: Railway Labor Executives' Association Additional Records 5571: Jacob Seidenberg Additional Arbitration Files 5583/6: Archives Organization File (AOF) Part 6 5584: National Archives and Records Service Copies of Federal Documentation on Black Workers 5588: David L. Cole Papers 5605: Jacob Seidenberg Additional Arbitration Records 5623: Brotherhood of Railroad Trainmen Legislative Board of New York Files 5635: Jacob Seidenberg Additional Arbitration Files 5666: Jacob Seidenberg Additional Arbitration Files 5706: Jacob Seidenberg Additional Arbitration Files 5711: UTU New York State Legislative Director Files 5728: Railway Labor Executives' Association Additional Records 5735: BRAC Additional Records 5756: Jacob Seidenberg Additional Arbitration Files 5806: U.S. National Mediation Board Agreements 5837: National Railroad Adjustment Board Case Files 5888: Emanuel Stein Papers 6039 MB: Railroad Memorabilia 6178/009: BLS Collection of Collective Bargaining Agreements (Part 9) 6178/017: BLS Collection of Collective Bargaining Agreements (Part 17) 6190: Jacob J. Kaufman Papers 6275: Tia Schneider Denenberg Arbitration Files 6287: Martin Scheinman Collection of Collective Bargaining Agreements
Railroads -- Labor unions -- New York (State); Strikes and lockouts -- Railroads -- New York (State); Long Island Railroad Company; New York (State). Metropolitan Transportation Authority.; United Transportation Union.
5743725
- Long Island Railroad Strike newspaper clippings, 1994 (Box 1)
  - Item 1: Belzer, M. (June 19, 1994). "Should LIRR Come Under Anti-Strike Law?" New York Newsday., News clipping (Box 1, Folder 0)
    Scope and Contents
    Article written by Cornell University ILR professor about the history of collective bargaining between the LIRR and its controlling entity, the Metropolitan Transportation Authority, and the United Transportation Union. Specifically, it focuses on the Railway Labor Act and New York State's Taylor Law, and how these apply to the LIRR. The article is annotated.
    Format: News clipping.
  - Item 2: Finder, A. (1994, June 21). "Ripples of L.I.R.R. Pact Not Likely to Reach City." New York Times., News clipping (Box 1, Folder 0)
    Article focuses on outcome of LIRR strike with focus on how the LIRR, because it is a railway subject to regulation under interstate commerce laws, are unlikely to effect the legality of strikes by New York City subway and bus workers
  - Item 3: Marks, P. (1994, June 21). "With Jabs at M.T.A. Chief, Cuomo Defends rail-Strike Pact." New York Times., News clipping (Box 1, Folder 0)
  - Item 4: Goodman, L. (1994, June 21). "LIRR deal puts gov, MTA boss on track for collision." New York Post., News clipping (Box 1, Folder 0)
  - Item 5: (1994, June 21). "LIRR strike: worse than nothing." New York Daily News., News clipping (Box 1, Folder 0)
    NY Daily News editorial
  - Item 6: Dicker, F. "[missing] labor vote in pushing rail act." New York Post., 1994; News clipping (Box 1, Folder 0)
  - Item 7: Horvath, A., Smith, A., & Johnson, J. (1994, June 18). "'No Excuse" Cuomo pushes for LIRR pact." Newsday., News clipping (Box 1, Folder 0)
  - Item 8: Rayman, G. (1994, June 18). "Commuters avoid rush-hour horror." Newsday., News clipping (Box 1, Folder 0)
  - Item 9: Clifford, T. & Rein, L. (1994, June 18). "LIRR talks resume." New York Daily News., News clipping (Box 1, Folder 0)
  - Item 10: Lyons, J. (1994, June 18). "Biz derailed by LIRR." New York Daily News., News clipping (Box 1, Folder 0)
  - Item 11: (1994, June 18). "LIRR: Nothing less than hostage taking." New York Daily News., News clipping (Box 1, Folder 0)
    Daily News editorial